trustedpros.ca 2016-10-27

# TrustedPros Privacy Policy

* * *

## PRIVACY POLICY - (INDIVIDUALS)

Effective **April** **9, 2015**

This privacy policy applies to any information collected or otherwise obtained on or through the website located at http://www.trustedpros.ca (the " **Website** ") and, unless otherwise specified, any other websites controlled or operated by TPI, which are accessible through the Website.

This privacy policy is effective as of the date set forth above. Personal information provided or collected prior to the above effective date shall be subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time such personal information was provided or collected. 

Titles and headings are provided for general reference and ease of use only, as information may be covered in more than one heading or under other headings.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, any personal information about you in our possession or under our control or any of our practices with respect to personal information, please contact TPI's privacy officer at [privacy@trustedpros.ca](mailto:privacy@trustedpros.ca).

**I. Collection of Personal Information**

TPI is committed to protecting your privacy. Unless expressly provided, personal information collected is for the sole purpose of the operation of this Website and providing the services offered through or in conjunction with this Website (collectively, the " **Services** "). 

_Registration_

Personal information is collected in conjunction with the creation of your account for the Website, namely your name, e-mail address, city and province (or territory) of residence, postal code and confirmation that you have reached the age of majority in the jurisdiction in which you reside. You may also choose to provide us with a telephone number. 

For individuals who become a business member, we will also collect information about your business in conjunction with the creation of such membership (and creation of a business member profile) and updating of such membership information and profile; such information may also include personal information.

_Financial Information_

We do not collect any personal information of a financial nature about individuals, except: (i) if an individual uses a personal credit card in conjunction with the purchase of a business membership; and/or (ii) if an individual becomes a business member and provides financial information relating to his or her business in conjunction with the creation of a business member profile. In such cases, your name, credit card number, expiration date and security code will be collected by TPI for the sole purpose of transmitting same to our payment gateway provider. Your credit card information is not retained by TPI. 

_Website and Services_

Personal information may also be collected in conjunction with your access and use of the Website and Services.  For example, if you post content on the Website (such as a job listing, testimonial or a rating or review), such posting will be associated to your account and any personal information contained in such posting will be accessible to other users of the Website.  TPI may monitor your use of the Website and Services and may create records of your use of the Website and Services.

This Website uses cookies.  A cookie is a piece of data tied to information about the user and stored on the user's computer. This Website uses both session cookies, which terminate when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain on your computer until manually deleted.

By setting a persistent cookie, we allow you not to have to log in with a password more than once, thereby saving time while accessing the Website. If you reject these cookies, you may still access and use the Website but your experience and/or access may be limited in some areas of the Website. 

TPI may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on its behalf and to monitor certain pages of the Website for the purpose of reporting web traffic, statistics, advertisement "click-throughs", and/or other activities on our site. These third party service providers may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous.

As is the case with most other websites, personal information may also be collected by TPI with respect to your system and your specific access to and use of the Website and Services. Such information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamps, number of clicks, cookies, clear gifs, user profiles and log files detailing access dates and times, webpages visited and features used.  A profile is stored information that TPI keeps on individual users that detail such users' viewing preferences, Website activities and interactions and exchanges with TPI.  Like most standard Website servers we use log files. 

_Third Party Posts_

The Website allows third parties to post messages and other content and, although our terms and conditions of use prohibit anyone from posting any personal information about someone else, it is possible that a third party may post personal information about you, in contravention with such terms and conditions. Any such personal information will be promptly removed upon us discovering its existence on the Website. If you come across any such personal information on the Website, please contact our privacy officer and such personal information will be promptly removed.

**II. Use of Personal Information**

As indicated above, we will use personal information obtained for the purposes of operating the Website and providing the Services.  This includes us communicating with you with respect to your use of the Website, your use of Services (including, for example, obtaining clarification or confirmation of Services requested and information submitted in conjunction with the obtaining of such Services), your account and responding to inquiries made by you.  This also includes allowing you to make postings in certain sections of the Website (such as job requests, personal anecdotes, testimonials, success stories, evaluations of contractors and suppliers, ratings, rankings and reviews and detailing of specific projects).  You understand and agree that to the extent you include personal information in a posting, such personal information will be posted on the Website and will be accessible to other users of the Website.

Likewise, if you are a business member and provide information about yourself in your profile or in a listing, such personal information will be accessible to other users of the Website. You understand that the information you provide in terms of creation of an account as a business member (other than payment information with respect to the purchase of a business membership) will be published on the Website and may otherwise be made available to other users of the Website. As indicated above, users of the Website may post content about business members and other contractors and service providers.  Where such a contractor or services provider is an individual, such content may include personal information. Although such personal information may be posted on the Website, such posting is prohibited by our terms and conditions of use and such personal information will be deleted from the Website when we become aware of its existence

The Website offers matching services in terms of job requests and contractors and suppliers.  To the extent you post a job request, the Services will attempt to match such job request to contractors and suppliers.  To the extent matches are found, your name along with any informaiton provided in the description input field will be provided to those matching contractors and suppliers. 

Similarly, we may from time to time contact you via e-mail about Services or other features of the Website or send you updates about the Website and the Services, including, newsletters and bulletins.  You may at any time opt out from receiving future communications by clicking on the opt-out hyperlink shown in such e-mail, at which time you will promptly be removed from the relevant distribution list.

Finally, collected information regarding access and usage of the Website and Services is tied to the users' personally identifiable information to improve the performance, security, content and features of the Website and delivery of Services (including, your accessing and use of the Website and Services), and to modify and/or expand Website functionality and nature and scope of Services.  Such information is also used to analyze trends, administer the Website, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

Users' profile information is also used to tailor, ease, improve, facilitate and accelerate a user's access and use of the Website and Services (e.g. by remembering user preferences and applying these to subsequent visits).

On rare occasions, TPI may send out strictly service related e-mail announcements. These communications are not promotional in nature.  For instance, if TPI's service is temporarily suspended on account of maintenance we might send users an e-mail advising them of this. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account which will prevent future communications of such sort. 

**III. Modification of Personal Information**

To the extent your personal information has changed or that our records are otherwise not accurate with respect to your personal information, please contact our privacy officer by e-mail at privacy@trustedpros.ca.  We will endeavour to update your personal information in a timely manner.

TPI may paraphrase, summarize, aggregate or compile feedback, ratings, reviews, rebuttals and/or testimonials and may edit these to correct typos, spelling and grammatical errors as well as obvious mistakes in terms of objective facts.

TPI reserves the right to deny requests to remove any feedback, ratings, reviews, rebuttals and/or testimonials from the Website, including members profile information associated with any such feedback, ratings, reviews, rebuttals and/or testimonials.

_Leads Notifications and Free Lead Notifications_

If a user either signs up for our free membership program or signs up for our premium (paid) membership service, that user will receive multiple communications from us via email. Other ways we contact members of our service professional network are via fax, and/or cell text (SMS) messaging. Members of our service professional network (or prospective members enrolled in a free trial) can designate which bulletins and communications they wish to receive and opt-in on our Website or by contacting customer service to receive leads in one or more of these formats.

**IV. Disclosure of Personal Information**

When you submit information to TPI, you authorize us to share this information with our service providers.  TPI shall ensure that any third party to whom it discloses your personal information has signed a contract which obligates such third party to safeguard your personal information, adhere to the same terms and conditions as those contained in this privacy policy and otherwise comply with applicable laws. 

Use certain Services and features of the Website will result in the disclosure of personal information.  For example, if you choose to select a contractor for a job posting or if you respond to a contractor who has indicated interest in a job posting, such contractor will receive your name and contact information.  Likewise, as previously indicated, postings made by you on the Website or through use of a Service will be accessible to other users of the Website.  To the extent such postings contain personal information, such personal information will be communicated to users who access such posting. Similarly, personal information about you which you include in a business profile will be accessible to other users of the Website.

Please note that if you post a review, testimonial, rating, ranking or other comment about a business member of the Website or any other contractor or service provider, such third party may post a reply or a rebuttal and such reply or rebuttal will be associated with your account and your original posting. If your posting includes personal information, it will be associated with such third party content.

TPI may create and share aggregated activity or statistical information with partners, advertisers or others, but such information will not contain personally identifiable information.

**V. Safeguarding of Personal Information**

Though we strive to preserve user privacy, due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will always remain confidential. You acknowledge and understand that the Internet is a public network and that communications on or through the Internet may be intercepted, misdirected, altered and/or deleted.  Likewise, e-mails and accounts may be spoofed and individuals impersonated.  Care should therefore be taken prior to disclosing personal information on or through the Website or to any users or purported users of the Website.

Likewise, we may disclose personal information when required by law (including by court order or in conjunction with police investigations or legal proceedings), when we have a belief that such action is necessary or advisable to comply with applicable laws, or when we believe that a user is violating the law, is a threat to others or himself/herself or is in personal danger. 

**VI. Mergers/Acquisitions/Restructuring**

In the event TPI (or any of its business units) is bought, sold, restructured or merges with another entity, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of such transaction. TPI may disclose your personal information to such entities and their advisors, provide it first ensures that each of them sign a non-disclosure agreement safeguarding your personal information and preventing them from making any use of the information outside of such proposed transaction or restructuring and any subsequent operation of TPI's business. 

**VII. Choice/Opt-in/Opt-out**

Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-in' in terms of having their information used for purposes not directly related to the operation of the Website and delivery of Services they have requested.  Such opt-in option is usually provided at the time of collection and/or in subsequent communications to the user. For example, our service request form has an 'opt-in' mechanism allowing users who submit a service request to elect to receive marketing material.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving these communications by selecting the opt-out hyperlink in the relevant email or by emailing us at [privacy@trustedpros.ca](mailto:privacy@trustedpros.ca).

You will be notified and your consent obtained when personal information collected through use of the Website is to be communicated to a third party (excluding our affiliates, service providers, or agents). We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**VIII. Links and Integrated Partnerships**

This Website contains links from and to other websites. Please be aware that this privacy policy does not apply to such websites and that personal information you disclose or that may otherwise be collected from you may not be subject to the same terms and conditions as those that apply with respect to TPI and the Website.  TPI is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave our Website and to read the privacy statements or policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by TPI in conjunction with the operation of the Website and delivery of Services.

**IX. Location of Storage Facilities**

This Website is hosted from facilities located exclusively within the province of Ontario, Canada. Your personal information may, however, be stored outside of the Province of Ontario to the extent we use service providers located outside of Ontario.  You acknowledge and understand that the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (Canada) may apply and otherwise affect the collection, use, disclosure, retention and destruction of your personal information.  Additional privacy legislation may also apply depending on the location of our service providers, our computer facilities or those of our service providers.

By creating an Account, and/or by accessing and using this Website and any service offered by or through this Website, you hereby consent and agree to the practices described in this privacy policy, including, without limitation, the collection, use, disclosure, retention, storage and destruction practices relating to your personal information.  Without limitation to the foregoing, you also agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy.

Previous versions of TrustedPros Inc. Privacy Policy can be found [here](https://trustedpros.ca/privacy-05102013.asp).  

* * *

## PRIVACY POLICY - BUSINESS MEMBERS

**Effective Date: April 10, 2013**

This privacy policy applies to any information collected or otherwise obtained on or through the website located at https://trustedpros.ca (the “ **Website** ”) and, unless otherwise specified, any other websites controlled or operated by TrustedPros Inc., which are accessible through the Website.

This privacy policy is effective as of the date set forth above. Personal information provided or collected prior to the above effective date shall be subject to the privacy policy in effect at the time such personal information was provided or collected. 

Titles and headings are provided for general reference and ease of use only, as information may be covered in more than one heading or under other headings.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this privacy policy, any personal information about you in our possession or under our control or any of our practices with respect to personal information, please contact TPI's privacy officer at privacy@trustedpros.ca.

**Collection of Personal Information**

TPI is committed to protecting your privacy. Unless expressly provided, data collected is for the sole purpose of the operation of this Website and providing the services offered through this Website (collectively, the “ **Services** ”). 

_Registration_

Personal information is collected in conjunction with the creation of your account for the Website, namely your name, e-mail address, city and province (or state) of residence, postal code (or zip code) and confirmation that you have reached the age of majority in the jurisdiction in which you reside. You may also choose to provide us with a telephone number.  Please note that to the extent you provide us with a  business address which is not your home address and/or business e-mail address, such information is not considered as being personal information and is therefore not subject to this privacy policy.

_Financial Information_

With respect to the processing of transactions, such as a purchase of any premium membership, we may collect financial information (such as your credit card number and expiration date, PayPal account particulars and the like), depending on the method of payment you choose.  Such information is then forwarded to our payment gateway for processing.  You will also be asked to provide information about your annual sales volumes (you may decline to provide this information without any limitation or restriction with respect to your registration).  Other than as previously described, we do not retain any such personal information of a financial nature about you. 

_Website and Services_

Personal information may also be collected in conjunction with your access and use of the Website and Services.  For example, if you post content on the Website (such as a message, business profile or rebuttal to a testimonial, a rating or review), such posting will be associated to your account and any personal information contained in such posting will be accessible to other users of the Website. 

TPI may monitor your use of the Website and Services and may create records of your use of the Website and Services.

This Website uses cookies.  A cookie is a piece of data tied to information about the user and stored on the user's computer. This Website uses both session cookies, which terminate when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which remain on your computer until manually deleted.

By setting a persistent cookie, we allow you not to have to log in with a password more than once, thereby saving time while accessing the Website. If you reject these cookies, you may still access and use the Website but your experience and/or access may be limited in some areas of the Website. 

TPI may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on its behalf and to monitor certain pages of the Website for the purpose of reporting web traffic, statistics, advertisement “click-throughs”, and/or other activities on our site. These third party service providers may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous.

As is the case with most other websites, personal information may also be collected by TPI with respect to your system and your specific access to and use of the Website and Services. Such information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamps, number of clicks, cookies, clear gifs, user profiles and log files detailing access dates and times, webpages visited and features used.  A profile is stored information that TPI keeps on individual users that detail such users’ viewing preferences, Website activities and interactions and exchanges with TPI.  Like most standard Website servers we use log files. 

**Use of Personal Information**

As indicated above, we will use personal information obtained for the purposes of operating the Website and providing the Services.  This includes us communicating with you with respect to your use of the Website, your use of Services (including, for example, obtaining clarification or confirmation of Services requested and information submitted in conjunction with the obtaining of such Services), your account and responding to inquiries made by you.  This also includes allowing you to make postings in certain sections of the Website (such as message-board posts, business profiles, portfolios, advertisements, referrals, and rebuttals to a testimonial, rating or review).  You understand and agree that to the extent you include personal information in a posting, such personal information will be posted on the Website and will be accessible to other users of the Website. 

The Website also provides users access to an online directory of business members who register on the Website, which directory will include the information you provide during the registration process (with the exception of any payment information you provide with respect to the payment of any membership fees). 

Likewise, the Website offers matching services in terms of job requests and contractors and suppliers.  To the extent you create a business profile, the Services will attempt to match such business profile to job requests and potential suppliers.  To the extent matches are found, your name, contact e-mail and other business information included in your business profile will be provided to the user creating the job request and, potentially, relevant suppliers.  Moreover, we may send you offers through email or otherwise which we deem relevant to your trade or line of business. You may at any time opt out from receiving future offers by clicking on the opt-out hyperlink shown in such e-mail, at which time you will be removed from the relevant distribution list within a 30 day period.

If you sign up for our free membership program or sign up for our premium (paid) membership service, you will receive multiple communications from us with respect to and in conjunction with the operation Website and the delivery of Services. Other ways we contact members of our service professional network are via fax, and/or cell text (SMS) messaging. Members of our service professional network (or prospective members enrolled in a Free Trial) can designate and opt-in on our Website or by contacting customer service to receive leads in one or more of these formats.

Similarly, we may from time to time contact you via e-mail about Services or other features of the Website or send you updates about the Website and the Services, including, newsletters and bulletins.   We may also from time to time contact you via e-mail about products and services of other members of the Website or other third parties.  You may at any time opt out from receiving future communications by clicking on the opt-out hyperlink shown in such e-mail, at which time you will be removed from the relevant distribution list within a 30 day period.

We sometimes partner with third parties who provide complimentary services or host portals providing access to the Website and/or the Services.  In conjunction with the foregoing, we may provide your name and e-mail address to such third parties for the sole purpose of allowing such third parties to contact you via e-mail about their services and other products, including newsletters and bulletins.  Each such third party is required to include in such communications a hyperlink or other manner of opting out from receipt of future communications from such third party. You may always contact us in the event of any problems or delays with respect to such un-subscription with respect to such communications.

Finally, collected information regarding access and usage of the Website and Services is tied to the users’ personally identifiable information to improve the performance, security, content and features of the Website and delivery of Services (including, your accessing and use of the Website and Services), and to modify and/or expand Website functionality and nature and scope of Services.  Such information is also used to analyze trends, administer the Website, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

Users’ profile information is also used to tailor, ease, improve, facilitate and accelerate a user's access and use of the Website and Services (e.g. by remembering user preferences and applying these to subsequent visits).

On rare occasions, TPI may send out strictly service related e-mail announcements. These communications are not promotional in nature.  For instance, if TPI’s service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an e-mail advising them of this. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account which will prevent future communications of such sort. 

**Modification of Personal Information**

To the extent your personal information has changed or that our records are otherwise not accurate with respect to your personal information, please contact our privacy officer by e-mail at privacy@trustedpros.ca.  We will endeavour to update your personal information in a timely manner.

TPI may paraphrase, summarize, aggregate or compile Feedback, Ratings, Reviews, Rebuttals and/or Testimonials and may edit these to correct typos, spelling and grammatical errors as well as obvious mistakes in terms of objective facts.

To the extent permitted by applicable laws, TPI reserves the right to deny requests to remove any business profile, referrals, or rebuttals to testimonials, Ratings, Reviews and/or Testimonials from the Website, including members profile information associated with any such business profiles, referrals, or rebuttals. 

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

When you submit information to TPI, you authorize us to share this information with our service providers.  TPI shall ensure that any third party to whom it discloses your personal information has signed a contract which obligates such third party to safeguard your personal information, adhere to the same terms and conditions as those contained in this privacy policy and otherwise comply with applicable laws. . 

Use certain Services and features of the Website will result in the disclosure of personal information.  For example, if you choose to respond to a project listing or if you contact a supplier who has also been matched with a project listing, the user who posted the project listing and any such supplier (as the case may be) will receive your name and contact information.  Likewise, as previously indicated, postings made by you on the Website or through use of a Service will be accessible to other users of the Website.  To the extent such postings contain personal information, such personal information will therefore be communicated to users who access such posting.

TPI may create and share aggregated activity or statistical information with partners, advertisers or others, but such information shall not contain personally identifiable information.

**Safeguarding of Personal Information**

Though we strive to preserve user privacy, due to the inherent nature of the Internet, we cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will always remain confidential.  You acknowledge and understand that the Internet is a public network and that communications on or through the Internet may be intercepted, misdirected, altered and/or deleted.  Likewise, e-mails and accounts may be spoofed and individuals impersonated.  Care should therefore be taken prior to disclosing personal information on or through the Website or to any users or purported users of the Website.

Likewise, we may disclose personal information when required by law (including by court order or in conjunction with legal proceedings), when we have a belief that such action is necessary or advisable to comply with applicable laws, or when we believe that a user is violating the law, is a threat to others or himself/herself or is in personal danger. 

**Mergers/Acquisitions/Restructuring**

In the event TPI (or any of its business units) is bought, sold, restructured or merges with another entity, users' personal information will, in most instances, be part of such transaction. TPI may disclose your personal information to such entities and their advisors, provide it first ensures that each of them sign a non-disclosure agreement safeguarding your personal information and preventing them from making any use of the information outside of such proposed transaction or restructuring and any subsequent operation of TPI’s business. 

**Choice/Opt-out**

Our users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to the operation of the Website and delivery of Services they have requested.  Such opt-out option is usually provided at the time of collection and/or in subsequent communications to the user. For example, our service request form has an 'opt-out' mechanism allowing users who submit a service request to elect not to receive any marketing material.

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving these communications by selecting the opt-out hyperlink in the relevant email or by emailing us at privacy@trustedpros.ca.

You will be notified when personal information collected through use of the Website is to be communicated to a third party (excluding our affiliates, service providers, or agents). We do this so our users can make an informed choice as to whether or not they should proceed with services that require an outside party.

**_Links and Integrated Partnerships_**

This Website contains links from and to other websites. Please be aware that this privacy policy does not apply to such websites and that personal information you disclose or that may otherwise be collected from you may not be subject to the same terms and conditions as those that apply with respect to TPI and the Website.  TPI is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites. We encourage you to be aware of this when you leave our Website and to read the privacy statements or policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by TPI in conjunction with the operation of the Website and delivery of Services.

**_Location of Computer Facilities_**

Your personal information may be stored outside of the Province of Ontario to the extent we use service providers located outside of Ontario.  This is presently the case as this Website is hosted from facilities located in the United States.  You acknowledge and understand that the _Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ (Canada) may apply and otherwise affect the collection, use, disclosure, retention and destruction of your personal information.  Additional privacy legislation may also apply depending on the location of our service providers, our computer facilities or those of our service providers.

**By creating an Account, and by accessing and using this Website and any service offered by or through this Website, you hereby consent and agree to the practices described in this privacy policy, including, without limitation, the collection, use, disclosure, retention, storage and destruction practices relating to your personal information.   Without limitation to the foregoing, you also agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy.**  

* * *

Previous versions of TrustedPros Inc. Privacy Policy can be found [here](https://trustedpros.ca/privacy-05102013.asp).
